Guide to the Otto Rank Papers,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series II: Cataloged Manuscripts
  - Menerfeld, Max Lord Byron und seine Schwester, [n.p.], May 1908, (12 page t.ms.) (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - Rosenthal, Tatjana Das gefahrliche Alter, [n.p.], 5 Jan. 1911, (17 page t.ms.) (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - Silberer, Herbert Das Zerstuckelungsmotiv in Mythos, (11 page t.ms.) (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - Silberer, Herbert Zur Symbolbildung, [n.p.], 1912, (17 pp pages) (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - Stekel, Wilhelm Fortschritte der Traumdeutung, (1 page newspaper) (Box 6, Folder 37)
  - Taft, Jessie Taft's obituaries for Rank, Pennsylvania, 1939 & 1940, (8 page t.ms. & newspaper) (Box 6, Folder 38)
  - Taft, Jessie The Time Element in Therapy, (19 pages) (Box 6, Folder 39)
  - Taft, Jessie Analysis of Taft's contacts with Rank, [n.p.], 1924-1939, (25 a.ms. & t.ms.) (Box 6, Folder 39a)
  - Taussig, Beatrice Rank and Rodin, (1 page) (Box 6, Folder 40)
  - Taussig, Beatrice Time and the Will, [n.p.], 5 March 1935 & 23 May 1935, (28 pages) (Box 6, Folder 41)
  - Tschizewskij, D. Zum Doppelganger problem bei Dostojevskij, [n.p.], 1931, (32 page t.ms.) (Box 6, Folder 42)
  - Wilbur, George [Rank's contribution to psychoanalysis], (12 pages) (Box 6, Folder 43)
  - Wirth, Herman Die heilige Urschrift der Menschheit, (24 page t.ms.) (Box 6, Folder 44)
  - Zimmerman, J. G. Weber die Einsamkeit, [n.p.], 1784, (9 pages) (Box 6, Folder 45)
  - [?] Miscellaneous, [n.p.], 30 Dec. 1934, (6 pages) (Box 6, Folder 46)
  - Unknown author Miscellaneous manuscript, (5 pages) (Box 6, Folder 47)
  - Miscellaneous manuscripts (Box 6, Folder 48)
- Series III: Cataloged Documents
  - Taft, Jessie Two admission tickets to Rank's lectures, New York & Philadelphia, 12 Nov 1926 & 192[?], (2 pieces p.d.) (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Rank, Otto Application for a stipend, [n.p.], 15 Nov. 1909, (3 page a.d.s.) (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Rank, Otto Army service, [n.p.], 1916 - 1918, (16 page p.d. & a.d.) (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Rank, Otto Library card, [n.p.], 1910, (1 page a.d.s.) (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Rank, Otto & Estelle Buel Marriage certificate for Otto Rank and Estelle Buel, Nevada, 27 July 1931, (1 page photocopy of p.d.) (Box 7, Folder 5)
    [Gift of E. James Lieberman]
  - Rank, Otto Military identification card with photo attached, Crakow, 30 Jan. 1918, (2 page ms.d.s.) (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Rank, Otto Receipts, Wien, 1913, (6 page t.d. & a.d.) (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Rank, Otto Receipts to Jessie Taft for payment for her psychoanalytic sessions with Rank, [n.p.], 1 Nov & 1 Dec 1926, (2 a.d.s.) (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Rank, Otto Receipt to Dorothy Hankins for payment for her psychoanalytic sessions with Rank, [Philadelphia], 1 April 1935, (1 page a.d.) (Box 7, Folder 9)
    [incl. envelope]
  - Rank, Otto Receipt to Dorothy Hankins for patment for her psychoanalytic session with Rank, [Philadelphia], 1 May 1935, (1 page a.d.) (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Rank, Otto Receipt to Dorothy Hankins for payment for her psychoanalytic sessions with Rank, [Philadelphia], 24 May 1935, (1 page a.d.) (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Rank, Otto Surrogates Court New York County account and agreement of distribution and settlement of Otto Rank's estate, New York County, [Nov] 1939, (27 page p.d.) (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Rank, Otto Miscellaneous drawing, (1 page photocopy of document) (Box 7, Folder 13)
- Series IV: Arranged Manuscripts
  - Subseries IV.1: Chronological Series, 1903 - 1939
    - Rank, Otto Tagebucher I, Wien, 1 Jan. 1903 - 22 Feb 1904, (93 page a.ms.) (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Rank, Otto Tagebucher II, Wien, 22 Feb 1904 - 30 Dec 1904, (104 page a.ms.) (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Rank, Otto Tagebucher III, Wien, 1 Jan 1905 - 8 April 1905, (56 page a.ms.) (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Rank, Otto Tagebucher IV, Wien, 10 April 1905 - 1 July 1905, (36 page a.ms.) (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Rank, Otto 4 Notebooks, [n.p.], 1903 - 1905, (95 page each. a.ms.) (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Rank, Otto Tagebucher I, [n.p.], 1903 - 1904, (80 page t.ms.) (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Rank, Otto Tagebucher II, [n.p.], 1904 - 1905, (78 page t.ms.) (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Rank, Otto Tagebucher III, [n.p.], 1905, (56 page t.ms.) (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Rank, Otto Tagebucher IV, [n.p.], 1905, (36 page t.ms.) (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Rank, Otto Tagebucher I (English tranlation), [n.p.], 1903 - 1904, (49 page t.ms.) (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Rank, Otto Tagebucher II (English trans.), [n.p.], 1904 - 1905, (33 page t.ms.) (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Rank, Otto Tagebucher III (English trans.), [n.p.], 1905, (16 page t.ms.) (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Rank, Otto Tagebucher IV (English trans.), [n.p.], 1905, (24 page t.ms.) (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Rank, Otto Gotzen (First draft), [n.p.], 1903, (26 page a.ms.) (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Rank, Otto Gotzen - Poems, [n.p.], 1903 - 1905, (19 page a.ms.) (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - Rank, Otto Der Freund, [n.p.], 1904, (13 page a.ms.) (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - Rank, Otto Tagebuchblatter eines Totgeborenen, [n.p.], 1904, (5 page a.ms.) (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - Rank, Otto Tagebuchblatter eines Totgeberenen, [n.p.], 1904, (5 page t.ms.) (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - Rank, Otto Traume und Versuche ihrer Deutung, [n.p.], 1904 - 1905, (24 page a.ms.) (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - Rank, Otto Das Wesen des Judentums (First draft), [n.p.], 1904, (3 page a.ms.) (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - Rank, Otto Das Werer des Judentums, [n.p.], 1905, (6 page a.ms.) (Box 8, Folder 21)
    - Rank, Otto Das Werer des Judentum, [n.p.], 1905, (5 page t.ms.) (Box 8, Folder 22)
    - Rank, Otto Homosexuelle Neigungen. Intro, 414-446, 458, [n.p.], 1906, (33 page a.ms.) (Box 9, Folder 23)
    - Rank, Otto Homosexuelle Neigungen. 390, 446a, 447-464, [n.p.], 1906, (19 page a.ms.) (Box 9, Folder 24)
    - Rank, Otto Homosexuelle Neigungen. 465-473, [n.p.], 1906, (8 page a.ms.) (Box 9, Folder 25)
      [See Manuscript Flat Box 166]
    - Rank, Otto Homosexuelle Neigungen. 447-522, 527-530, [n.p.], 1906, (78 a.ms.) (Box 9, Folder 26)
    - Rank, Otto Homosexuelle Niegungen. 530-543, 563-575, [n.p.], 1906, (25 page a.ms.) (Box 9, Folder 27)
    - Rank, Otto Homosexuelle Neigungen. 544-562, [n.p.], 1906, (18 page a.ms.) (Box 9, Folder 28)
    - Rank, Otto Homosexuelle Neigungen. 576-666, [n.p.], 1906, (90 page a.ms.) (Box 9, Folder 29)
    - Rank, Otto Homosexuelle Neigengum. 667-686, 689, 694-751, [n.p.], 1906, (69 page a.ms.) (Box 9, Folder 30)
    - Rank, Otto Homosexuelle Neigengum. Loose notes., [n.p.], 1906, (64 page a.ms.) (Box 9, Folder 31)
    - Rank, Otto Homosexuelle Neigungen. Clippings, [n.p.], 1906, (4 page Clipping) (Box 9, Folder 32)
    - Rank, Otto Der Kunstler. Ch. 1, 2. Fifth draft carbon with corrections, [n.p.], 1907, (48 page t.ms.) (Box 9, Folder 33)
    - Rank, Otto Der Kunstler. Intro., [n.p.], 1907, (14 page a.ms.) (Box 9, Folder 34)
    - Rank, Otto Der Kunstler. Ch. 1, 2. First draft, [n.p.], 1907, (27 page a.ms.) (Box 9, Folder 35)
    - Rank. Otto Der Kunstler. Ch. 1, 2. Second draft., [n.p.], 1907, (31 page a.ms.) (Box 9, Folder 36)
    - Rank, Otto Der Kunstler. Ch. 1, 2. Third draft., [n.p.], 1907, (30 page a.ms.) (Box 9, Folder 37)
    - Rank, Otto Der Kunstler. Ch. 1, 2. Fourth draft., [n.p.], 1907, (51 page t.ms.) (Box 9, Folder 38)
    - Rank, Otto Der Kunstler. Ch. 1, 2. Final draft., [n.p.], 1907, (48 page t.ms.) (Box 9, Folder 39)
    - Rank, Otto Der Kunstler, [n.p.], 1907, (50 page t.ms. &a.ms.) (Box 9, Folder 40)
    - Rank, Otto Der Kunstler, [n.p.], 1907, (50 page t.ms. &a.ms.) (Box 9, Folder 41)
    - Rank, Otto Der Kunstler. Unbound copy., [n.p.], 1907, (11 page t.ms.) (Box 9, Folder 42)
      [Incomplete]
    - Rank, Otto Der Kunstler. Two unbound copies., [n.p.], 1907, (100 page t.ms.) (Box 9, Folder 43)
    - Rank, Otto Der Kunstler. Preface., [n.p.], 1918, (7 page a.ms.) (Box 9, Folder 44)
    - Rank, Otto Der Kunstler. Intro., [n.p.], 1918, (7 page t.ms.) (Box 9, Folder 45)
    - Rank, Otto Der Kunstler. p. 1-26., [n.p.], 1918, (26 page Page proof.) (Box 9, Folder 46)
    - Rank, Otto Der Kunstler, [n.p.], 1918, (67 page Page proof) (Box 9, Folder 47)
    - Clippings 1907 - 1910, (8 page) (Box 9, Folder 48)
      [See Manuscript Flat Box 172]
    - Rank, Otto Der Kunstler. Preface to the translation., [n.p.], 1918, (6 page a.ms.) (Box 9, Folder 49)
    - Rank, Otto Der Kunstler. English translation., [n.p.], 1918, (49 page t.ms.) (Box 9, Folder 50)
    - Rank, Otto Der Kunstler. Loose notes., [n.p.], 1918, (4 page a.ms.) (Box 9, Folder 51)
    - Rank, Otto Der Kunstler. Loose notes., [n.p.], 19??, (2 page a.ms.) (Box 9, Folder 52)
    - Rank, Otto Das Pumpgenie, [n.p.], 1907, (74 page a.ms.) (Box 9, Folder 53)
    - Rank, Otto Der Mythus von der Geburt. p. 61-93, [n.p.], 1909, (24 page t.ms.) (Box 10, Folder 54)
    - Rank, Otto Der Mythus von der Geburt des Helden (unbound), [n.p.], 1909, (93 page t.ms.) (Box 10, Folder 55)
    - Rank, Otto Der Mythus Geburt, [n.p.], 1909, (1 page a.ms.) (Box 10, Folder Oversize)
      [Oversize. In Mapcase 14-12-3]
    - Rank, Otto Der Mythus... (Photocopy of the chart), [n.p.], 1909, (1 page a.ms. (photocopy)) (Box 10, Folder 56)
    - Rank, Otto Der Mythus. Notes of Judaism., [n.p.], 1909, (7 page a.ms.) (Box 10, Folder 57)
    - Rank, Otto Der Mythus, [n.p.], 1909, (22 page a.ms. & t.ms.) (Box 10, Folder 58)
    - Rank, Otto Der Mythus, [n.p.], 1909, (2 page t.ms.(unbound. Loose notes.)) (Box 10, Folder 59)
    - Rank, Otto Der Mythus, [n.p.], 1922, (7 page a.m.s. & clipping) (Box 10, Folder 60)
      [Loose notes and clippings]
    - Rank, Otto Der Mythus. Letter from J. Niffgen., [n.p.], 7 July 1930, (1 page a.l.s.) (Box 10, Folder 61)
    - Rank, Otto Ein Traum der selbst deutet, [n.p.], 1910, (99 page a.ms.) (Box 10, Folder 62)
    - Rank, Otto Ein Traum. English translation., [n.p.], 1910, (49 page t.ms. (carbon)) (Box 10, Folder 63)
    - Rank, Otto Ein Traum. English translation., [n.p.], 1910, (41 page a.ms. & t.ms.) (Box 10, Folder 64)
    - Rank, Otto Ein Traum, [n.p.], 1910, (17 page notes) (Box 10, Folder 65)
    - Rank, Otto Ein Beitrag zum Narcissism, [n.p.], 1911, (27 page a.ms.) (Box 10, Folder 66)
    - Rank, Otto Ein Beitrag zum Narcissismus, [n.p.], 1911, (23 page a.l.s. & clippings) (Box 10, Folder 67)
    - Rank, Otto Ein Beitrag, [n.p.], 1911, (2 page a.ms.) (Box 10, Folder 68)
    - Rank, Otto Die Lohengrimsage, [n.p.], 1911, (200 page a.ms.) (Box 10, Folder 70)
    - Rank, Otto Die Lohengrimsage, [n.p.], 1911, (23 page a.ms. &t.ms.) (Box 10, Folder 71)
    - Rank, Otto Lohengrinsage, [n.p.], 1911, (35 page a.ms. notes) (Box 10, Folder 72)
    - Rank, Otto Lohengrinsage, [n.p.], 1911, (12 page a.ms.) (Box 10, Folder 73)
    - Rank, Otto Miscellaneous notes, [n.p.], 1911 - 1912, (5 page a.ms.) (Box 10, Folder 74)
    - Rank, Otto Clippings, [n.p.], 1911-1912 (Box 10, Folder 75)
    - Rank, Otto Volkerpsychologische Paralleil zu den, [n.p.], 1912, (2 a.ms. notes) (Box 10, Folder 76)
      [Gift of Estelle B. R. Simon]
    - Rank, Otto Inzest-Motiv, [n.p.], 1912, (43 a.ms. draft) (Box 10, Folder 77)
    - Rank, Otto Inzest-Motiv, [n.p.], 1912, (7 page a.ms.) (Box 10, Folder 78)
      [Ch. 2. First draft.]
    - Rank, Otto Inzest-Motiv, [n.p.], 1912, (5 page a.ms.) (Box 10, Folder 79)
      [Ch. 2. Second draft.]
    - Rank, Otto Inzest-Motiv, [n.p.], 1912, (76 page t.ms.) (Box 10, Folder 80)
      [Ch. 23. Unbound copy.]
    - Rank, Otto Inzest-Motiv, [n.p.], 1912, (8 page a.ms. notes) (Box 10, Folder 81)
    - Rank, Otto Inzest-Motiv, [n.p.], 1912, (3 page t.ms.) (Box 10, Folder 82)
    - Rank, Otto Inzest-Motiv, [n.p.], 1912, (63 page t.ms.) (Box 10, Folder 83)
      [Ch. 21, 22, 23. Unbound copy.]
    - Rank, Otto Inzest-Motiv, [n.p.], 1912, (70 page a.ms. notes) (Box 10, Folder 84)
    - Rank, Otto Inzest-Motiv, [n.p.], 1912, (80 page a.ms. notes) (Box 10, Folder 85)
    - Rank, Otto Das Inzest-Motiv bei Richard Wagner., [n.p.], Feb 1927, (20 page Journal) (Box 10, Folder 87)
    - Rank, Otto Inzest Motiv, [n.p.], 1926, (70 page a.ms.) (Box 11, Folder 88)
      [See Manuscript Flat Box 169. Intro, Ch. 1]
    - Rank, Otto Inzest-Motiv, [n.p.], 1926, (80 page t.ms.) (Box 11, Folder 89)
      [Ch. 2, 3. Unbound copy.]
    - Rank, Otto Inzest-Motiv, [n.p.], 1926, (100 page t.ms.) (Box 11, Folder 90)
      [Ch. 4, 5. Unbound copy.]
    - Rank, Otto Inzest-Motiv, [n.p.], 1926, (50 page t.ms.) (Box 11, Folder 91)
      [Ch. 6, 7. Unbound copy.]
    - Rank, Otto Inzest-Motiv, [n.p.], 1926, (77 page t.ms.) (Box 11, Folder 92)
      [Ch. 8, 9. Unbound copy.]
    - Rank, Otto Inzest-Motiv, [n.p.], 1926, (19 page t.ms.) (Box 11, Folder 93)
      [See Manuscript Flat Box 169. Ch. 11.]
    - Rank, Otto Inzest-Motiv, [n.p.], 1926, (30 page t.ms.) (Box 11, Folder 94)
      [ Ch 13, 17. Unbound copy]
    - Rank, Otto Inzest-Motiv, [n.p.], 1926, (35 page t.ms.) (Box 11, Folder 95)
    - Rank, Otto Die mythischen Vorlaufer der Tragodie, (4 page t.ms.) (Box 11, Folder 96)
    - Rank, Otto Inzest-Motiv. Clippings I., (15 page newspapers) (Box 11, Folder 97)
    - Rank, Otto Inzest-Motiv. Clippings II., (10 page newspapers) (Box 11, Folder 98)
    - Rank, Otto Inzest-Motiv. Clippings III., (35 page newspapers) (Box 11, Folder 99)
    - Rank, Otto Inzest-Motiv. Clippings in French., (15 page newspapers) (Box 11, Folder 100)
    - Rank, Otto Inzest-Motiv. Clippings., [n.p.], 1912 - 1926, (45 page newspapers) (Box 11, Folder 101)
    - Rank, Otto Inzest-Motiv. Unpublished third edition. Intro. First draft., (51 page t.ms.) (Box 12, Folder 102)
      [3 copies. See Manuscript Flat Box 169.]
    - Rank, Otto Inzest-Motiv. Unpublished third edition. Ch. 1. First draft., (34 page t.ms.) (Box 12, Folder 103)
      [2 copies]
    - Rank, Otto Inzest-Motiv. Unpublished third edition. Ch. 2. First draft., (34 page t.ms.) (Box 12, Folder 104)
    - Rank, Otto Inzest-Motiv. Unpublished third edition. Ch. 3. First draft., (40 page t.ms.) (Box 12, Folder 105)
      [3 copies. See Manuscript Flat Box 169]
    - Rank, Otto Inzest-Motiv. Third edition. Introduction. Second draft., (16 page t.ms.) (Box 12, Folder 106)
    - Rank, Otto Inzest-Motiv. Unpublished third edition. Intro, Ch. 1-5. Second draft., (130 page t.ms.) (Box 12, Folder 107)
      [See Manuscript Flat Box 170]
    - Rank, Otto Inzest-Motiv. Third edition. Ch. 6, 7. Second draft., (52 page t.ms.) (Box 12, Folder 108)
    - Rank, Otto Inzest-Motiv. Unpublished third edition. Ch. 8-12. Second draft., (140 page t.ms.) (Box 12, Folder 109)
    - Rank, Otto Inzest-Motiv. Unpublished third edition. Ch. 13, 14. Second draft., (42 page t.ms.) (Box 12, Folder 110)
    - Rank, Otto Inzest-Motiv. Unpublished third edition. Ch. 15, 16. Second draft., (45 page t.ms.) (Box 12, Folder 111)
    - Rank, Otto Inzest-Motiv. Third edition. Intro, ch. 1-4., (100 page t.ms.) (Box 12, Folder 112)
    - Rank, Otto Inzest-Motiv. Third edition. Ch. 5-13., (150 page t.ms. (carbons)) (Box 12, Folder 113)
    - Rank, Otto Inzest-Motiv. Third edition. Ch. 14-16., (70 page t.ms.) (Box 12, Folder 114)
    - Rank, Otto Inzest-Motiv. Third edition. Ch. [17, 18], (45 page t.ms.) (Box 12, Folder 115)
    - Rank, Otto Inzest-Motiv. Unpublished third edition. Miscellaneous., (35 page t.ms.) (Box 12, Folder 116)
    - Rank, Otto Inzest-Motiv. Third edition. German & French notes., (80 page a.ms. &t.ms.) (Box 12, Folder 117)
    - Rank, Otto Inzest-Motiv. Outline in French. Third edition., (21 page t.ms.) (Box 12, Folder 118)
    - Rank, Otto Inzest-Motiv. Third edition. Intro, ch. 1, 4, 5. English translation., (100 page t.ms.) (Box 12, Folder 119)
      [ORA gift 1986]
    - Rank, Otto Traumdeutung, [n.p.], 1914, (60 a.ms.) (Box 12, Folder 120)
      [See Manuscript Flat Box 167]
    - Rank, Otto Traumdeutung. p. 157-178, 190-221, 238-252., [n.p.], 1914, (66 page t.ms.) (Box 12, Folder 121)
    - Rank, Otto Traumdeutung, [n.p.], 1914, (9 page a.ms.) (Box 12, Folder 122)
    - Rank, Otto Traumdeutung. Intro., [n.p.], 1914, (20 page a.ms.) (Box 12, Folder 123)
    - Rank, Otto Traumdeutung. Ch: Traum u. Dichtung., [n.p.], 1914, (17 page a.ms.) (Box 12, Folder 124)
    - Rank, Otto Traumdeutung. Ch: Traum u. Dichtung, [n.p.], 1914, (2 page t.ms.) (Box 12, Folder 125)
    - Rank, Otto Traumdeutung. Appendix 1 & 2., [n.p.], 1914, (47 page a.ms.) (Box 12, Folder 126)
    - Rank, Otto Traumdeutung. Unbound copy., [n.p.], 1914, (30 page t.ms.) (Box 13, Folder 127)
    - Rank, Otto Traumdeutung. Notes., [n.p.], 1914, (45 page a.ms.) (Box 13, Folder 128)
    - Rank, Otto Traumdeutung. p. 1-4, 22-24, [n.p.], 1914, (9 page a.ms. &t.ms.) (Box 13, Folder 129)
    - Rank, Otto Traumdeutung. Clippings., (18 page newspapers) (Box 13, Folder 130)
      [See Manuscript Flat Box 173]
    - Rank, Otto Technik der Traumdeutung. p. 1-96., (96 page t.ms.) (Box 13, Folder 131)
    - Rank, Otto Uber Traume und ihre Deutung, (13 page a.ms.) (Box 13, Folder 132)
      [a.ms.]
    - Rank, Otto Uber Traume und ihre Deutung, (11 page t.ms.) (Box 13, Folder 133)
    - Rank, Otto Beispiel eines verklappten Odipustraumes, (6 page a.ms.) (Box 13, Folder 134)
    - Rank, Otto Dreams. Notes, (30 page a.ms.) (Box 13, Folder 135)
    - Apel, Paul Hans Sommerstopers Hollenfahrt, (8 page a.ms.) (Box 13, Folder 136)
    - Rank, Otto Der Doppelganger. Ch. 1, 2., [n.p.], 1914, (40 page a.ms.) (Box 13, Folder 137)
    - Rank, Otto Der Doppelganger, [n.p.], 1914, (60 page a.ms.) (Box 13, Folder 138)
      [This refers to the same material in folder 139]
    - Rank, Otto Der Doppelganger, [n.p.], 1914, (60 page a.ms.) (Box 13, Folder 139)
    - Rank, Otto Der Doppelganger. Notes., [n.p.], 1914, (45 page t.ms. & a.ms.) (Box 13, Folder 140)
    - Rank, Otto Der Doppelganger. English translation., [n.p.], 1914, (40 page t.ms.) (Box 13, Folder 141)
    - Rank, Otto Der Doppelganger. Clippings., [n.p.], 1914, (8 page newspapers) (Box 13, Folder 142)
    - Rank, Otto Der Doppelganger. Clippings., [n.p.], 1933-34, (2 page newspapers & magazines) (Box 13, Folder 143)
    - Rank, Otto Der Doppelganger. Clippings., (15 page newspapers & magazines) (Box 13, Folder 144)
    - Rank, Otto Der Doppelganger. Revision of 1925 edition., (140 page t.ms.) (Box 13, Folder 145)
    - Rank, Otto Homer, [n.p.], 1917, (36 page t.ms.) (Box 13, Folder 146)
    - Rank, Otto Homer. Ch: Die dichterische Phantasiebildung., [n.p.], 1917, (50 page a.ms.) (Box 13, Folder 147)
      [See Manuscript Flat Box 168]
    - Rank, Otto Homer: Ch: Mccanlay's Lay's of Ancient Rome, [n.p.], 1917, (20 page a.ms.) (Box 13, Folder 148)
    - Rank, Otto Homer book cover, (1 Hardbound book cover) (Box 13, Folder 149)
    - Rank, Otto Homer. Loose notes., [n.p.], 1917, (17 page a.ms.) (Box 14, Folder 150)
    - Rank, Otto Homer. Clippings., (4 page newspapers) (Box 14, Folder 151)
    - Rank, Otto Das "Schauspiel" in "Hamlet", (18 page a.ms.) (Box 14, Folder 152)
    - Freud, Sigmund Nibelungelied in Homer, [n.p.], 21 Feb. 1909, (1 page a.ms.) (Box 14, Folder 153)
      [See Manuscript Flat Box 174 (cataloged manuscript)]
    - Freud, Sigmund Homer, [n.p.], 1908-1909, (2 page a.ms.) (Box 14, Folder 154)
    - Rank, Otto Das Volksepos, [n.p.], 1917, (20 page t.ms.) (Box 14, Folder 156)
    - Rank, Otto Das Volksepos. Table of Contents., [n.p.], 1917, (2 page a.ms.) (Box 14, Folder 157)
    - Rank, Otto Das Volksepos, [n.p.], 1917, (1 page a.ms. photocopy) (Box 14, Folder 158)
    - Rank, Otto Volksepos. Part II Sicht. Phantasiebildung. Draft., [n.p.], 1917, (12 page a.ms.) (Box 14, Folder 159)
    - Rank, Otto Volksepos. Part III. Homer., [n.p.], 1917, (60 page a.ms.) (Box 14, Folder 160)
    - Rank, Otto Volksepos. Part IV. Nibelungenlied., [n.p.], 1917, (4 page a.ms.) (Box 14, Folder 161)
    - Rank, Otto Volksepos. Part II., [n.p.], 1917, (39 page t.ms.) (Box 14, Folder 162)
    - Rank, Otto Volksepos. Loose notes., [n.p.], 1917, (30 page a.ms. &t.ms.) (Box 14, Folder 163)
    - Rank, Otto Volksepos. Loose clippings., [n.p.], 1917, (15 page newspapers) (Box 14, Folder 164)
    - Rank, Otto Das Volksepos. Unbound copy., [n.p.], 1917, (15 page a.ms. & t.ms.) (Box 14, Folder 165)
    - Rank, Otto Das Volksepos. Two unbound copies., [n.p.], 1917, (12 page t.ms.) (Box 14, Folder 166)
    - Rank, Otto Das Volksepos. Clippings., (2 page newspapers) (Box 14, Folder 167)
    - Rank, Otto Das Volksepos. Part IV. Das Nibelungenlied. Lecture. 1854, [n.p.], 1917, (12 page a.ms.) (Box 14, Folder 168)
    - Rank, Otto Psychoanalytische Beitrage. Ch. 13., [n.p.], 1919, (40 page t.ms.) (Box 14, Folder 169)
    - Rank, Otto Psychoanalytische Beitrage, [n.p.], 1919, (60 page a.ms.) (Box 14, Folder 170)
    - Rank, Otto Psychoanaylische Beitrage, [n.p.], 1919, (60 page t.ms.) (Box 14, Folder 171)
    - Rank, Otto Psychoanalytische Beitrage. Notes., [n.p.], 1919, (15 page a.ms.) (Box 14, Folder 172)
    - Rank, Otto Psychoanalytische Beitrage zur Mythenforschung. Loose notes., [n.p.], 1922, (7 page a.ms.) (Box 14, Folder 173)
    - Rank, Otto Don Juan. Draft., [n.p.], 1922, (35 page a.ms.) (Box 14, Folder 174)
    - Rank, Otto Don Juan, [n.p.], 1922, (102 page a.ms.) (Box 14, Folder 175)
    - Rank, Otto Don Juan. Loose notes., [n.p.], 1922, (20 page a.ms.) (Box 14, Folder 176)
    - Rank, Otto Don Juan, [n.p.], 1922, (30 page t.ms.) (Box 14, Folder 177)
    - Rank, Otto Don Juan, [n.p.], 1922, (20 page t.ms. (proof)) (Box 14, Folder 178)
    - Rank, Otto Don Juan., [n.p.], 1922, (104 p (2 copies). t.ms.) (Box 14, Folder 179)
    - Rank, Otto Don Juan. English translation., [n.p.], 1922, (54 page t.ms. (carbons)) (Box 14, Folder 180)
    - Rank, Otto Don Juan. Clippings., [n.p.], 1922, (30 page newspapers) (Box 14, Folder 181)
    - Rank, Otto Perversion und Neurose, [n.p.], 1922, (37 page a.ms.) (Box 15, Folder 182)
    - Rank, Otto Perversion und Neurose, [n.p.], 1922, (12 page t.ms. (unbound page proof)) (Box 15, Folder 183)
    - Rank, Otto Perversion und Neurose. Draft., [n.p.], 1922, (34 page a.ms.) (Box 15, Folder 184)
    - Rank, Otto Perversion und Neurose. Loose notes., [n.p.], 1922, (8 page a.ms.) (Box 15, Folder 185)
    - Rank, Otto Clippings, [n.p.], 1923, (40 page newspapers) (Box 15, Folder 186)
    - Rank, Otto Eine Neurosenalyse in Traumen. Draft., [n.p.], 1924, (14 page a.ms.) (Box 15, Folder 187)
    - Rank, Otto Eine Neurosenanalyse, [n.p.], 1924, (100 page t.ms. (carbon)) (Box 15, Folder 188)
    - Rank, Otto Eine Neurosenanalyse, [n.p.], 1924, (110 page t.ms.) (Box 15, Folder 189)
    - Rank, Otto Eine Neurosenanalyse. Loose notes., [n.p.], 1924, (15 page a.ms.) (Box 15, Folder 190)
    - Rank, Otto Eine Neurosenanalyse in Traumen. Loose notes., [n.p.], 1924, (1 page a.ms.) (Box 15, Folder 191)
      [Gift of Estell B. R. Simon, 1990]
    - Rank, Otto Eine Neurosenanalyse. Dreams., [n.p.], 1924, (120 page a.ms. & t.ms.) (Box 15, Folder 192)
    - Rank, Otto Eine Neurosenanalyse. Dreams II., [n.p.], 1924, (100 page a.ms. & t.ms.) (Box 15, Folder 193)
    - Rank, Otto Eine Neurosenanalyse in Traumen. Book reviews., [n.p.], 1924, (8 page t.ms.) (Box 15, Folder 194)
    - Rank, Otto & Ferenczi, S&or Entwicklungsziele der Psychoanalyse, [n.p.], 1924, (35 page a.ms.) (Box 15, Folder 195)
    - Rank, Otto& Ferenczi, S&or Entwicklungsziele. First draft., [n.p.], 1924, (55 page t.ms.) (Box 15, Folder 196)
    - Rank, Otto Entwicklungsziele. Second draft., [n.p.], 1924, (53 page t.ms.) (Box 15, Folder 197)
    - Rank, Otto& Ferenczi, S&or Entwicklunhsziele. Final draft., [n.p.], 1924, (68 page t.ms.) (Box 15, Folder 198)
    - Rank, Otto & Ferenczi, S&or Entwicklungsziele. Notes., [n.p.], 1924, (25 page a.ms.) (Box 15, Folder 199)
    - Rank, Otto & Ferenczi, S&or Entwicklungsziele., [n.p.], 1924, (60 page t.ms.) (Box 15, Folder 200)
    - Rank, Otto Entwicklungsziele. Ch. 6., [n.p.], 1924, (4 t.ms.) (Box 15, Folder 201)
    - Clippings 1923-1924, ( newspapers) (Box 15, Folder 202)